Register of the James B. Donovan papers
Hoover Institution Archives
James B. Donovan papers
1919-1976
72013
Hoover Institution Archives
90 manuscript boxes, 7 oversize boxes, 9 envelopes (44.9 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, studies, drafts of book manuscripts, scrapbooks, notes, photographs, and printed matter relating to the United States Office of Scientific Research and Development and the Office of Strategic Services during World War II, the Nuremberg war crime trials, the Rudolf Abel-Gary Powers spy exchange, the Cuban prisoner exchange following the Bay of Pigs landing, and the New York City Board of Education. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Donovan, James B. (James Britt), 1916-1970
Location of Original Materials
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Access
Boxes 2, 6, 14, 19, 24, 34, 38-40, 43, 65-66, 68, 75-76, 78-80, 85-88, 92-93 and envelopes A, C-I are available for use. The remainder of the collection is closed for preservation purposes. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for more information.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1972.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1916 February 19 Born, New York City
1937 A.B., Fordham University
1940 L.L.B., Harvard University
1942-194 Associate General Counsel, Office of Scientific Research and Development
1943-1945 General Counsel, Office of Strategic Services
1945 Assistant to the U.S. Chief Prosecutor, International Military Tribunal, Nuremberg
1950-1970 Partner, Waters and Donovan, New York City
1961-1963 Vice President, New York Board of Education
1963-1965 President, New York Board of Education
1964 Author, Strangers on a Bridge
1967 Author, Challenges
1968-1970 President, Pratt Institute
1970 January 19 Died, New York City
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, studies, drafts of book manuscripts, scrapbooks, notes, photographs, and printed matter relating to the United States Office of Scientific Research and Development and the Office of Strategic Services during World War II, the Nuremberg war crime trials, the Rudolf Abel-Gary Powers spy exchange, the Cuban prisoner exchange following the Bay of Pigs landing, and the New York City Board of Education.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Abel, Rudolf, 1903-1971.; New York (N.Y.) Board of Education; Powers, Francis Gary, 1929-1977.; United States. Office of Scientific Research and Development.; United States. Office of Strategic Services.; Cuba--History--Invasion, 1961.; Education--New York (N.Y.); Espionage.; Nuremberg Trial of Major German War Criminals, Nuremberg, Germany, 1945-1946.; War crime trials.; World War, 1939-1945--Secret service.
- Biographical File, 1919-1969 (Boxes 1-10)
  Scope and Contents note
  Material relating to naval service, early law career, participation in professional and charitable organizations, financial material, family history, clippings, appointments books and correspondence, arranged by subject.
  - General
    - General. Award certificate, clippings, class reunion materials, 1947-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Address book (Folder 2)
    - Appointment books
      - 1952-1965 (Folder 3-10)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Biographies and eulogies (Folder 3)
    - Clippings (Folder 4)
    - Correspondence
      - General
      - 1961-1965 (Folder 5)
      - 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 1-10)
      - 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 1-7)
      - Family (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Get well wishes (Folder 2-3)
  - Invitations (Folder 4-5)
  - Family history materials. Clippings and pamphlets, 1919-1955 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Financial materials. Correspondence and other materials related to investments (Folder 2-30)
  - Legal career
    - General. Clippings, letters and miscellany, Includes a letter from Felix Frankfurter, 1939-1951. (Folder 31)
    - American Bar Association
      - Insurance, Negligence and Compensation Law Section. Correspondence, minutes, memoranda, reports, 1965-1966 (Folder 32)
      - International Law Section, Special Committee on Diplomatic Immunity. Correspondence, reports and printed material, 1962-1964 (Folder 33-34)
    - Guild of Catholic Lawyers of the City of New York. Printed material, notes, legal documents, letters, and a speech transcript relating to a decision by the New York City school administration to omit The Nation from their subscription list, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - New York Daily News. Legal documents relating to multiple cases, ca. 1939-1941 (Folder 2)
  - Naval service. Personnel materials, letters, memoranda, and pamphlets, 1943-1958 (Folder 3)
  - Public service
    - Pratt Institute
      - Non-printed material. Chronological file, primarily correspondence, 1969 Sept.-Oct. (Folder 4)
      - Printed material. Pamphlets, newsletters, and miscellany, 1965-1969 (Folder 5)
      - Printed material (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Saint Francis College
      - General. Press releases, yearbook, clippings, pamphlets, correspondence, memoranda, budgets and financial reports, and minutes, 1963-1969 (Folder 2-11)
      - General (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1961-1965 (Folder 2-8)
  - Senatorial campaign, 1962. Also includes material relating to earlier Democratic Party activities, 1956-1962 (Folder 9-21)
  - Senatorial campaign (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
- Speeches and Writings, 1958-1968 (Boxes 10-19)
  Drafts, proofs, and printed copies of speeches and writings with related correspondence, clippings, books reviews, and miscellany, arranged alphabetically.
  - General
    - General. Miscellaneous editorials, book reviews, citations, speeches, clippings, correspondence, draft and printed articles, 1962-1968 (Box 10, Folder 5-12)
    - Correspondence. Speaking engagements
      - 1958-1963 (Box 11, Folder 1-9)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 12, Folder 1-21)
      - 1964-1967 (Box 13, Folder 1-9)
  - Challenges, 1967. Correspondence, printed material and two printed copies of the book, 1966-1968 (Box 14, Folder 1-4)
  - "The Defense of Colonel Abel," Teleplay typescript, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - "Defense of a Spy"
    - Rough draft, n.d. (Folder 6-7)
    - Typescript with annotations and corrections (Folder 8)
  - "Re: U.S. vs. Abel," Typescript draft with annotations, n.d. (Folder 9)
  - Strangers on a Bridge, 1964
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1965-1967 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Atheneum Press, 1959-1966 (Folder 2)
      - Congratulatory letters
        - 1964 (Folder 3-12)
        - 1965 (Box 16, Folder 1-3)
      - French publishers, 1964-1965 (Folder 4)
    - Desmond, Charles S. Foreward by (Folder 5)
    - Documents
      - Abel, Rudolf, commutation of sentence, 1962 (Folder 6)
      - Barrett, E.L., "The Fourth Amendment" (Folder 7)
      - Donovan's Supreme Court argument (Folder 8)
      - Kahn's attempt at decoding Hayhanen's and Abel's messages (Folder 9)
    - Reviews
      - General (Folder 10)
      - French and German (Folder 11)
      - Saturday Evening Post excerpts (Folder 12)
    - Manuscripts
      - General. Untitled typescripts relating to Abel trial, n.d. (Folder 13-14)
      - Drafts. Typescripts
        - Earlier draft, with annotations and corrections (Box 17, Folder 1-3)
        - Later draft, with editorial corrections (Folder 4-6)
      - Galley proofs (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
      - Galley proofs (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Abel-Powers Spy Exchange File, 1957-1964 (Boxes 20-33)
  Correspondence, briefs, court statements, background studies, lists, reports, notes, affidavits, search warrants, trial notes, trial transcripts and exhibits, and diary relating to the Abel Spy Case and the exchange of Rudolf Abel for Gary Powers. Includes letter of congratulations from President Kennedy and correspondence with Abel.
  - Abel, Rudolf Ivanovich
    - Affidavit, U.S. Court of Appeals, Second Circuit, Criminal No. 45094 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Affidavits for search warrants (Folder 2)
    - Appendix. Two annotated printed copies of documents relating to legal appeals to the U.S. Court of Appeals, Second Circuit, and the U.S. Supreme Court, 1958 (Folder 3)
    - "Art Today,", n.d. (Folder 4)
    - Comments to Debevoise about the jury during their selection (Folder 5)
    - Correspondence
      - Bailey, John M., 1957 (Folder 6)
      - Federal Bureau of Investigation, Special Agent in Charge, 1957 (Folder 7)
      - Russian Embassy, Washington, D.C., 1957 (Folder 8)
    - Deportation proceedings, notice, 1957 June 20 (Folder 9)
    - Disposal of personal property (Folder 10)
    - Eviction notice, New York Municipal Court, 1957 August 8 (Folder 11)
    - Immigration hearing (Folder 12)
    - Notes on the case (Folder 13)
    - Order to Show Cause and Notice of Hearing, U.S. Department of Justice, 1957 June 20 (Folder 14)
    - Power of attorney
      - For J.B. Donovan, 1958 (Folder 15)
      - For David Levine, 1957 July 24 (Folder 16)
    - Property belonging to (Folder 17)
    - Record of sworn statement, 1957 June 24 (Folder 18)
    - Warrant for Arrest of Alien, U.S. Department of Justice, 1957 June 20 (Folder 19)
  - Abel, Rudolf Ivanovich vs. United States of America, Supreme Court
    - Petition for certiorari, 1958 August (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
    - 1958 October
      - Brief for petitioner, 1958 November 25 (Folder 4)
      - Brief for the United States (Folder 5)
      - Brief for the United States in opposition (Folder 6)
      - Reply briefs for petitioner
        - 1958 September 15 (Folder 7)
        - 1959 January 15 (Folder 8)
      - Supplemental brief for petitioner (Folder 9)
    - 1958 November
      - Briefs for petitioner, No. 263, 1958 November 25 (Folder 10-12)
      - John's brief, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Memos to J. B. Donovan (Folder 2)
      - Notes by J. B. Donovan (Folder 3)
    - 1959 October
      - Supplemental brief for the U.S. on Reargument (Folder 4)
      - Supplemental reply brief for petitioner, 1959 October 27 (Folder 5)
  - "The Abel Case," Outline of events, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Abel-Donovan correspondence, list (Folder 7)
  - Abel-Donovan meetings, list (Folder 8)
  - Abel file index (Folder 9)
  - Assistants list (Folder 10)
  - Briefs distribution, 1958-1960 (Folder 11)
  - Briefs distribution, 1959-1960 (Folder 12)
  - Byers, Mortimer W. (Folder 13)
  - CIA award (Folder 14)
  - Calendar of key dates for post-trial period (Folder 15)
  - Citations and opinions (Folder 16)
  - Clark, Robert R. (Folder 17)
  - Correspondence
    - Abel, Hellen, 1959-1961 (Folder 18)
    - Abel, Rudolf I., 1958-1964 (Folder 19)
    - America magazine article, 1960 October (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Anderson, Andrew E., 1962 (Folder 2)
    - Armstrong, Vayne M., 1957 (Folder 3)
    - Arnold, Suel O., 1962 (Folder 4)
    - Ashley, Charles H., 1962 (Folder 5)
    - Asmuth, William A., 1962 (Folder 6)
    - Autograph seekers, 1961-65 (Folder 7)
    - Averbach, Albert, 1962 (Folder 8)
    - Barnas, Mrs. Julius C., 1962 (Folder 9)
    - Barry, John R., 1962 (Folder 10)
    - Beakes, O. C., 1962 (Folder 11)
    - Beha, James J., 1962 (Folder 12)
    - Bell, J. Raymond, 1962 (Folder 13)
    - Benjamin, Robert M., 1958 (Folder 14)
    - Bennett, Alfred C., 1962 (Folder 15)
    - Boudin, Leonard B., 1960 (Folder 16)
    - Bower, Roger, 1962 (Folder 17)
    - Bradford, A. Lee, 1962 (Folder 18)
    - Brennan, Justice, 1960 (Folder 19)
    - Brenner, Thelma L., 1962 (Folder 20)
    - Breslin, Jimmy, n.d. (Folder 21)
    - Breslin, John J., 1962 (Folder 22)
    - Brinkley, David, 1962 (Folder 23)
    - Broderick, Joseph L., 1959 (Folder 24)
    - Brooklyn Bar Association, 1958-1960 (Folder 25)
    - Brown, Mrs. Thomas J., 1962 (Folder 26)
    - Bugbee, J. M., 1962 (Folder 27)
    - Burger, George J., 1962 (Folder 28)
    - Burrelle's Press Clipping Bureau, 1959-1962 (Folder 29)
    - Bushby, Wilkie, 1957 (Folder 30)
    - Butcher, Margaret, 1962 (Folder 31)
    - Byers, Mortimer W., 1962 (Folder 32)
    - Byrne, Brendan, 1962 (Folder 33)
    - Carbonara, E. Vernon, 1962 (Folder 34)
    - Carey, Kay and Paul, 1962 (Folder 35)
    - Carpenter, William H., 1962 (Folder 36)
    - Carroll, George, 1962 (Folder 37)
    - Carson, Ellis H., 1957-1962 (Folder 38)
    - Cassidy, William, 1962 (Folder 39)
    - Castellano, Edward, 1962 (Folder 40)
    - Catlin, Robert I., 1962 (Folder 41)
    - Chan, Mrs. Allyn, 1962 (Folder 42)
    - Chapman, Ralph, 1957 (Folder 43)
    - Chase, Carter B., 1959 (Folder 44)
    - Clark, Allen B., 1958 (Folder 45)
    - Clark, Russell J., 1959 (Folder 46)
    - Clarke, George W., 1960 (Folder 47)
    - Clavin, Joseph P., 1962 (Folder 48)
    - Clay, Lucius D., 1962 (Folder 49)
    - Coghlin, John W., 1962 (Folder 50)
    - Colavito, William J., 1962 (Folder 51)
    - Coleridge, David, 1962 (Folder 52)
    - Connolly, Edward J., 1959 (Folder 53)
    - Connor, John T., 1962 (Folder 54)
    - Considine, Robert B., 1959 (Folder 55)
    - Corkern, Robert W., 1962 (Folder 56)
    - Cornell Law School lecture, April 14, 1962 (Folder 57-58)
    - Coronet article, October 1960 (Folder 59)
    - Corroon & Reynolds Group, 1958 (Folder 60)
    - Cox, Robert M., 1962 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Crackpot letters, 1962 (Folder 2)
    - Cramton, Roger C., 1959 (Folder 3)
    - Cross, J. Harry, 1958 (Folder 4)
    - Cummings, Walter J., 1957-1960 (Folder 5)
    - Dahinden, Blanche, 1962 (Folder 6)
    - Davenport, Henry J., 1957 (Folder 7)
    - Davidson, Sidney W., 1959 (Folder 8)
    - Debevoise, Thomas M., 1957-1959 (Folder 9)
    - Deegan, Thomas J., 1962 (Folder 10)
    - Demas, George C., 1962 (Folder 11)
    - Dempsey, James, 1962 (Folder 12)
    - Desmond, Charles S., 1962 (Folder 13)
    - DeWitt, Paul B., 1958 (Folder 14)
    - Dickinson, Edward T., 1962 (Folder 15)
    - Doak, James B., 1962 (Folder 16)
    - Dodd, Thomas J., 1957 (Folder 17)
    - Donellan, Irma, 1957 (Folder 18)
    - Donovan, Marie, 1962 (Folder 19)
    - Donovan, Martin A., 1962 (Folder 20)
    - Donovan, Michael J., 1962 (Folder 21)
    - Dorr, C. A., 1957 (Folder 22)
    - Dowd, Joseph J., 1962 (Folder 23)
    - Dowling, J. Eudin, 1957 (Folder 24)
    - Driggs, Adrian P., 1962 (Folder 25)
    - Drimmer, Isidor, 1958 (Folder 26)
    - Duke, Angier Biddle, 1957 (Folder 27)
    - Dulles, Allen W., 1959-1962 (Folder 28)
    - Durkin, William J., 1959 (Folder 29)
    - Eager, Pat H., 1957 (Folder 30)
    - Edelstein, David N., 1962 (Folder 31)
    - Ennis, Edward J., 1959 (Folder 32)
    - Farrell, Edwin F., 1958 (Folder 33)
    - Faude, John P., 1957 (Folder 34)
    - Fay, Rollo E., 1957-1962 (Folder 35)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation, Special Agent in Charge, 1959 (Folder 36)
    - Fennell, Thomas F., 1958 (Folder 37)
    - Fey, Joseph L., 1962 (Folder 38)
    - Fleming, William H., 1962 (Folder 39)
    - Floberg, John F., 1962 (Folder 40)
    - Forsythe, Carl S., 1962 (Folder 41)
    - Fox, William Logan, 1962 (Folder 42)
    - Fraiman, Arnold G., 1957-1959 (Folder 43)
    - Friedenberg, Daniel M., 1957-1962 (Folder 44)
    - Friedlander, Alan J., 1958 (Folder 45)
    - Friedman, Irwin E., 1957-1962 (Folder 46)
    - Fritz, George J., 1962 (Folder 47)
    - Fulton, Mary Ann, 1962 (Folder 48)
    - Gibney, Frank, 1957-1958 (Folder 49)
    - Gilbert, Charles E., 1961 (Folder 50)
    - Gilmore, Robert N., 1962 (Folder 51)
    - Gleeson, Brother, 1962 (Folder 52)
    - Goddard, R. H. I., 1957 (Folder 53)
    - Goess, Frederick V., 1962 (Folder 54)
    - Gorman, Donald, 1962 (Folder 55)
    - Graver, William J., 1962 (Folder 56)
    - Gray, Mark W., 1960 (Folder 57)
    - Greenbaum, Edward S., 1959 (Folder 58)
    - Griswold, Erwin N., 1962 (Folder 59)
    - Gross, K. Frederick, 1959 (Folder 60)
    - Gruenewald, Louis A., 1962 (Folder 61)
    - Guffanti, Bruno A., 1957 (Folder 62)
    - Hall, Thomas K., 1958 (Folder 63)
    - Hammel, Paul A., 1962 (Folder 64)
    - Hanley, Dexter L., 1959 (Folder 65)
    - Hanson, Elisha, 1959 (Folder 66)
    - Harnett, T. A., 1958 (Folder 67)
    - Harris, William C., 1962 (Folder 68)
    - Hay, Harold F., 1962 (Folder 69)
    - Hazard, Leland, 1959 (Folder 70)
    - Heard, Murray W., 1958 (Folder 71)
    - Herbert, Edwin S., 1957-1958 (Folder 72)
    - Herd, Mrs. J. V., 1957 (Folder 73)
    - Hicks, Robert W., 1957 (Folder 74)
    - Hocker, Lon, 1962 (Folder 75)
    - Houston, Lawrence, 1958-1962 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Houston, Oscar R., 1960 (Folder 2)
    - Howard, John G., 1962 (Folder 3)
    - Johnson, Louis, 1958-1962 (Folder 4)
    - Journal of Insurance Information article, 1962 June-August
    - Kating, William, 1959 (Folder 5)
    - Kay, Tyler, 1962 (Folder 6)
    - Keane, John, 1962 (Folder 7)
    - Keating, Paul F., 1962 (Folder 8)
    - Keck, Caroline K., 1962 (Folder 9)
    - Kellogg, E. Ray, 1962 (Folder 10)
    - Kennedy, Harold V., 1957 (Folder 11)
    - Kennedy, Jennie, 1962 (Folder 12)
    - Kennedy, John F., 1962 (Folder 13)
    - Kennedy, Robert F., 1962 (Folder 14)
    - Kenney, Roger, 1962 (Folder 15)
    - Kenney, William S., 1959 (Folder 16)
    - Kerrigan, R. Emmett, 1962 (Folder 17)
    - Klauberg, Charles J., 1962 (Folder 18)
    - Knight, Louise, 1962 (Folder 19)
    - Kobre, Samuel L., 1965 (Folder 20)
    - Komoroff, Sam, 1962 (Folder 21)
    - Kotchka, Joe, 1962 (Folder 22)
    - Kruger, A. & H., 1962 (Folder 23)
    - Kruger, Holly, 1962 (Folder 24)
    - Lauterbach, Leon A., 1962 (Folder 25)
    - Lavender, Robert A., 1962 (Folder 26)
    - Lawler, Joseph, 1962 (Folder 27)
    - Lemmon, Vestal, 1957-1962 (Folder 28)
    - Lenihan, Joseph J., 1957 (Folder 29)
    - Letters from students, 1958-1966 (Folder 30)
    - Levine, Morton G., 1962 (Folder 31)
    - Lindeman, Bard, 1962-1965 (Folder 32)
    - Louisiana Bar Journal article, 1964 August (Folder 33)
    - Love, Francis, 1962 (Folder 34)
    - Lovell, Stanley P., 1962 (Folder 35)
    - Lowenstein, Edith, 1959 (Folder 36)
    - Luce Press Clipping Bureau, 1959 (Folder 37)
    - Lutnicki, Victor A., 1957 (Folder 38)
    - MacDonald, Will T., n.d. (Folder 39)
    - McGee, Joseph J., 1957 (Folder 40)
    - McGinley, L. J., 1959 (Folder 41)
    - McGinty, Jerome F., 1962 (Folder 42)
    - McGrath, E. J., 1962 (Folder 43)
    - McGrath, Francis A., 1958 (Folder 44)
    - McGugin, Dan E., 1962 (Folder 45)
    - McGurn, Barrett, 1962 (Folder 46)
    - McMahon, Stanton D., 1957-1962 (Folder 47)
    - McMullen, Frank J., 1962 (Folder 48)
    - McVean, David B., 1958 (Folder 49)
    - Magazine articles, 1957-1962 (Folder 50)
    - Mahoney, Robert F., 1962 (Folder 51)
    - Mahoney, Robert J., 1960 (Folder 52)
    - Maloney, Herbert W., 1962 (Folder 53)
    - Mancill, Frank H., 1957 (Folder 54)
    - Mann, Abby, 1960 (Folder 55)
    - Marbach, Gertrude R., 1962 (Folder 56)
    - Maroney, Kevin T., 1958 (Folder 57)
    - Mattison, William C., 1957-1959 (Folder 58)
    - Maxwell, Alan C., 1959 (Folder 59)
    - Mearin, R. J., 1962 (Folder 60)
    - Merrell, Louis J., 1957-1959 (Folder 61)
    - Monaghan, Gerald E., 1966 (Folder 62)
    - Moore, Robert, 1957 (Folder 63)
    - Morris, Stanley C., 1959 (Folder 64)
    - Morse, Robert A., 1962 (Folder 65)
    - Mortola, Edward J., 1962 (Folder 66)
    - Murchison, John D., 1962 (Folder 67)
    - Murphy, Mildred, 1957 (Folder 68)
    - Murphy, Ray, 1958 (Folder 69)
    - Murtagh, John M., 1962 (Folder 70)
    - Muste, A. J., 1962 (Folder 71)
    - Nasmith, Augustus, 1957-1962 (Folder 72)
    - National Bureau of Casualty Underwriters, 1962 (Folder 73)
    - National Lawyers Guild, 1959 (Folder 74)
    - Navarre, Joseph A., 1962 (Folder 75)
    - New York University Law Review, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Nolan, John E., 1959 (Folder 2)
    - Norvell, Woody, 1962 (Folder 3)
    - Oberst, Paul, 1959 (Folder 4)
    - O'Brien, Joseph F., 1962 (Folder 5)
    - O'Connor, John J., 1959 (Folder 6)
    - O'Hara, William J., 1962 (Folder 7)
    - Omsberg, Howard S., 1958 (Folder 8)
    - Pack, George, 1962 (Folder 9)
    - Pascal, Horace E., 1962 (Folder 10)
    - Pearle, Theodore, 1962 (Folder 11)
    - Peter F. Reilly's Fire-Proof Warehouse, 1959 (Folder 12)
    - Petrosino, Al, 1962 (Folder 13)
    - Pfeffer, Leo, 1958 (Folder 14)
    - Pollack, Milton, 1962 (Folder 15)
    - Powers, Francis Gary, n.d. (Folder 16)
    - Powers, Oliver, 1961 (Folder 17)
    - Pratt, John H., 1959 (Folder 18)
    - Pryor, Frederic L., 1962-1963 (Folder 19)
    - Pryor, Millard M., 1962-1963 (Folder 20)
    - Putzell, Edwin J., 1957 (Folder 21)
    - Quigley, Edward, 1962 (Folder 22)
    - Rabkin, Sol, 1960-1962 (Folder 23)
    - Randall, John D., 1959 (Folder 24)
    - Reidy, Daniel J., 1957-1962 (Folder 25)
    - Reisler, Raymond, 1958-1962 (Folder 26)
    - Rieser, Robert M., 1958-1962 (Folder 27)
    - Rigney, Edward D., 1957 (Folder 28)
    - Roberts, R. A., 1962 (Folder 29)
    - Robinson, Alan O., 1957-1962 (Folder 30)
    - Rodgers, Churchill, 1958 (Folder 31)
    - Rodgers, James, 1957 (Folder 32)
    - Rohan, Thomas E., 1959 (Folder 33)
    - Rosenberg, Maurice, 1958-1962 (Folder 34)
    - Ross, John, 1962 (Folder 35)
    - Rudd, Irving, 1957 (Folder 36)
    - Sallows, Leora, 1962 (Folder 37)
    - Saracino, John J., 1962 (Folder 38)
    - Sargent, J. W., 1957 (Folder 39)
    - Savage, John J., 1962 (Folder 40)
    - Schanley, John, 1957 (Folder 41)
    - Schoemer, John R., 1958 (Folder 42)
    - Schulberg, Stuart, 1961-1962 (Folder 43)
    - Shalleck, Milton, 1962 (Folder 44)
    - Shirley, Wayne, 1962 (Folder 45)
    - Silver, Charles, 1962 (Folder 46)
    - Silverman, Burton, 1958 (Folder 47)
    - Silversides, H. T., 1962 (Folder 48)
    - Smith, Mrs. C., 1962 (Folder 49)
    - Smith, James J., 1957 (Folder 50)
    - Smith, Joseph H., 1962 (Folder 51)
    - Smith, Kenneth O., 1962 (Folder 52)
    - Snorf, Lowell D., 1963 (Folder 53)
    - Spence, J. B., 1962 (Folder 54)
    - Spohn, Fred, 1962 (Folder 55)
    - Stoll, Herman, 1962 (Folder 56)
    - Storey, Robert G., 1957-1962 (Folder 57)
    - Tabatchnik, Ben, 1962 (Folder 58)
    - Taeffner, W. E., 1962 (Folder 59)
    - Tellalian, Aram H., 1957 (Folder 60)
    - Terbell, Floyd O., 1962 (Folder 61)
    - Thomas, D. C., 1958 (Folder 62)
    - Thompson, G. Vernon, 1957 (Folder 63)
    - Timbers, Mrs. Charles J., 1962 (Folder 64)
    - Tompkins, William F., 1957-1960 (Folder 65)
    - Tondel, Lyman M., 1960 (Folder 66)
    - Tonery, James T., 1962 (Folder 67)
    - Torgerson, Jean T., 1962 (Folder 68)
    - Tracy, Gerard B., 1957 (Folder 69)
    - True magazine article, 1962 September (Folder 70)
    - Tuttle, Esther, 1962 (Folder 71)
    - Uihlein, Henry, 1962 (Folder 72)
    - U.S. Court of Appeals. Second Circuit., 1958. (Folder 73)
    - U.S. Department of Justice, Solicitor General, 1960 (Folder 74)
    - U.S. Supreme Court, Chief Justice, 1959 (Folder 75)
    - U.S. Supreme Court, Clerk, 1958-1960 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Vail, George D., 1958-1962 (Folder 2)
    - Vandenheuvel, William J., 1957 (Folder 3)